Hello everyone, welcome back
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine,
welcome back everyone.
So what are we talking about today, Marco?
We are going to the flower shop.
Okay, so this is an
intermediate level lesson
and we're going to
be learning about the
different kinds of flowers
you can buy at a flower shop.
So we've got a guy here who's probably
trying to say something to someone he loves.
Yeah, I think he
did something to his
girlfriend or wife and well,
that's the typical thing, right?
You do something wrong so
you've got to get her flowers.
And that's why women
are often very nervous when
their husband or boyfriend gives them flowers
because she's thinking, what did he do?
What did he do wrong?
All right, so let's listen to the
dialogue and we'll be back soon.
Hello sir, how may I help you?
I would like to buy some flowers
please, something really nice.
I see, may I ask what the occasion is?
It's not really an occasion,
it's more like I'm sorry.
Very well, this
arrangement here is very
popular among regretful
husbands and boyfriends.
It has a dozen long
stem red roses with a
couple of sunflowers
and a single orchid that
stands out, includes
a small teddy bear to
achieve the effect of
immediate forgiveness.
I think I'm going to need more
than just a dozen red roses and a bear.
What else do you recommend?
Hmm, well this is our, I'm
sorry I cheated on you package,
two dozen red roses lined
with tulips, carnations and lilies.
The fragrance and beauty of this flower
arrangement is sure to make her forgive you.
I don't think that's going to cut it, I
need something bigger and better.
I'm sorry sir, but what exactly did you do?
Well, I may have accidentally
insinuated that she is getting chubbier.
Get out of my store you jerk.
All right, we're back so what do you think,
is this really like a bad thing to do?
Heck yeah, no really?
Well, no one wants to hear that
someone thinks they're fat, okay?
And chubbie is maybe not as bad as fat, but
the guy could have been a little bit nicer.
All right, so we'll give our listeners
some advice towards the end of the lesson.
So now why don't we take a look at all
the flower names in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay, this first flower
is a beautiful one and
it has delicious seeds
that people like to eat.
It's called a sunflower.
A sunflower, all right, so
that's a yellow flower, right?
It's bright yellow and in the middle is
orange and the stems are very, very long.
And thick.
So it's a tall flower.
Okay, sunflower and yeah, as you
mentioned, some people eat sunflower seeds.
They're like the little salty one, right?
That's right.
They're really good.
All right, next is an orchid.
Okay, an orchid is a
beautiful flower and
they're often grown just one at
a time and people collect orchids.
So these can be very, very expensive.
They're very expensive.
And they come in all
shaped sizes and colors.
Okay, an orchid.
Now what about a tulip?
A tulip is another
pretty flower and I think
they're most famous in
Holland for their tulips.
Because this actually used to be the
kind of money that they would use.
This was their currency for many years.
So they used tulips.
They used tulips.
And the tulip flower is kind of
like a, it's like a champagne glass.
It's tall and it's, it's kind
of empty in the middle.
Oh, that's interesting.
So next time somebody
says, do you think
money grows on trees
and Holland, it literally did?
Well, almost.
Almost.
All right.
What about a carnation?
Okay, a carnation is
another pretty flower
and they come, I think,
in red pink and white?
Yeah.
I've mostly seen white carnations.
And, you know, flower giving,
there's a whole definition to it, right?
So yeah, every flower
is symbolic of something
red, red roses are for
love and carnations,
I think are generally
friendship or either
friendship or like when
someone die, I'm not sure.
Right.
But you can give them
somebody's passed away.
Really?
I'm not sure how to look it up.
But carnation is another
very, very common
flower that you'll see
in many different colors.
Okay.
The next flower is also really common.
It's a lily.
All right.
A lily is a beautiful flower and
usually you see these on water.
So water lilies, for example, is it
another name you might hear?
Okay.
A water lily or just a regular lily.
And next we have the
most common of all the
flowers, but we've
had a little twist to it.
It's a long stem rose.
Right.
So rose, everyone knows.
Rose by any other name with smell of
sweet texture, wrote a lot about roses.
In this case, we're
talking about long stem
roses and we talked
about this with sunflowers.
The stem is the green
part that grows out
of the ground and you think
of the flower as the head.
And so the stem is actually the connector
between the ground and the flower.
Okay.
So these types of
roses have a really long
stem, so they're very nice to
maybe give one of them away.
That's right.
And you see, for example, at the opera, you
see singers, people throw these roses at
them and they pick
them up and they're so
long, the stems are so long and
they collect them in their arms.
And so that's a long stem rose.
All right.
Interesting.
Okay.
Why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the second time?
Let's keep a lookout for these
flower names and their pronunciation.
And we'll come back in a little bit.
Hello, sir.
How may I help you?
I would like to buy some flowers, please.
Something really nice.
I see.
May I ask what the occasion is?
It's not really an occasion.
It's more like I'm sorry.
Very well.
This arrangement here is very popular
among regretful husbands and boyfriends.
It has a dozen long
stem red roses with a
couple of sunflowers
and a single orchid that
stands out includes
a small teddy bear to
achieve the effect of
immediate forgiveness.
I think I'm going to need more
than just a dozen red roses and a bear.
What else do you recommend?
Hmm.
Well, this is our, I'm sorry,
I cheated on you, package.
Two dozen red roses lined
with tulips, carnations, and lilies.
The fragrance and beauty of this flower
arrangement is sure to make her forgive you.
I don't think that's going to cut it.
I need something bigger and better.
I'm sorry, sir, but what
exactly did you do?
Well, I may have accidentally
insinuated that she is getting chubbier.
Get out of my store, you jerk.
All right, we're back.
So in this dialogue, we had
a lot of interesting phrases.
So let's look at them
now in fluency builder.
A lot of these phrases
Marco have to do
with, well, what the guy did
wrong in today's dialogue.
And so the first one is to cheat on.
So the woman offered him the, I'm
sorry, I cheated on you, package, right?
So it's like an arrangement of flowers that
usually people buy when they cheat it on
their boyfriend or girlfriend.
Right.
And so in this case, to cheat
on means to see another person.
So if you're married to a
woman, seeing someone
else, you know, having
a date or romantic
encounter with another
person is cheating on your wife.
So you're cheating on your wife,
and you use it like this, cheat on, right?
Cheet on.
So he cheated on her, or they
were both cheating on each other.
Okay.
So cheat on, not a good thing.
Not a good thing.
All right.
So he was explaining to her that wasn't
enough, the arrangement wasn't enough.
And he said, I don't
think that's going to cut it.
Well, okay.
You've probably heard
the word cut before,
but in this case, Marco, we're talking
about to be able to cut some to cut it.
So that's not going to cut
it or it's not going to cut it.
It's not going to be enough.
Exactly.
So that's not quite what I'm looking for.
It's not enough.
He wants bigger and better.
He wants more.
And so for example, we could say, you know
what, this dessert's not going to cut it.
We need something much fancier.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
So to be good enough for.
So it took me good enough for.
All right.
Very good.
And then he was
explaining to the shop lady
what happened and he said,
well, I accidentally insinuated.
Okay.
To insinuate is to suggest.
So I could say, hey, you're really chubby.
That's not an insinuation.
Right.
That's a statement.
But I could say, oh, you're
looking a little bit round and aside.
That's an insinuation because I'm
suggesting without saying something.
Right.
So you're saying something indirectly.
He was insinuating that his
girlfriend was getting chubby.
Chubby.
So chubby.
Yes.
In this case, we're talking about
being round or a little bit overweight.
Right.
So it's not really saying fat.
No.
Fat is rude.
Right.
Chubby is, you know, it's
a little bit extra pounds.
Yeah.
Like maybe you had a little bit too much
ice cream over the past couple months.
All right.
Very good.
So why don't we listen to the dialogue
for the last time and we'll be back.
Hello, sir.
How may I help you?
I would like to buy some flowers, please.
Something really nice.
I see.
May I ask what the occasion is?
It's not really an occasion.
It's more like I'm sorry.
Very well.
This arrangement here is very popular among
with grateful husbands and boyfriends.
It has a dozen long stem
red roses with a couple
of sunflowers and a single
orchid that stands out.
It includes a small teddy bear to achieve
the effect of immediate forgiveness.
I think I'm going to need more
than just a dozen red roses and a bear.
What else do you recommend?
Hmm.
Well, this is our, I'm sorry,
I cheated on you, package.
Two dozen red roses lined
with tulips, carnations, and lilies.
The fragrance and beauty of this flower
arrangement is sure to make her forgive you.
I don't think that's going to cut it.
I need something bigger and better.
I'm sorry, sir, but what
exactly did you do?
Well, I may have accidentally
insinuated that she is getting chubbier.
Get out of my store, you jerk.
All right, so if you
make a mistake like as a
guy, right, you give
flowers to your girlfriend.
What about women giving flowers to guys?
Is that common?
Do you think that's possible?
Can you do that?
I'm sure you can do it, but I
don't know if it's as common.
Um, like I think as a guy, I wouldn't
really feel comfortable receiving flowers.
Really?
I mean, I would be
touched by the gesture
and I would be like,
oh, that's really sweet,
but like flowers is a little
bit too feminine, I think.
Generally, I think it's a one-sided thing.
So you can get flowers
for your mother or you
can get flowers for a
friend or if someone,
you know, passed away, you
can get flowers for their family.
Right.
But in a romantic situation,
rarely do you get flowers to a guy.
So if you want to say, I'm sorry
to a guy, what do you give him?
Um, season tickets
to his favorite football.
Yeah, that works.
Or a game for his playstation or
offering a new coat of paint on his car.
I don't know.
Have you never given a gift to
somebody like saying, I'm sorry?
No.
No, you don't make mistakes.
I like to use my words.
Ah, that's good.
Yeah, this is kind of interesting.
Why do we do this?
So why do we give
gifts to people as a token
or as a demonstration
of our regretfulness?
Well, can I get personal for a second?
I just was thinking about
this in terms of engagement.
So why do people give a
ring when they get engaged?
So it's like--
Because people like things
that glitter, you know?
It's like distract the
woman and she'll say, yes.
And so it's the similar thing
with flowers and forgiveness.
You say, oh gosh, these
flowers are so beautiful.
Of course I forgive you.
Oh, they're so pretty.
They smell so-- It's like
distraction from the matter at hand.
Right.
Oh, maybe that's it.
I don't know.
If you disagree with me, please-- It
was a very wise man who invented this.
Absolutely.
All right.
So if you have any questions,
doubts, or comments,
please come to our
website, www.englishpot.
com, and we'll
see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.